from enfield high school in enfield
connecticut Jeremy Bowie Jeremy
Jeremy's parents took him to their
native country of Vietnam two summers
ago where he saw devastating poverty
that in his words ripped my heart to
pieces he was stunned he said by the
daily struggle of peasants to earn a
living the primitive homes they lived in
and the inability of their children to
go to school because of the cost Jeremy
desperately wanted to do something to
help the families he met there not just
to survive but to break the stubborn
cycle that perpetuates poverty and
suffering from generation to generation
after turning home Jeremy decided the
answer was education if he could raise
money to provide scholarships for the
children of poor Vietnamese villagers
then perhaps they could one day good
good jobs that could pull their families
out of poverty working with his two
brothers Jeremy filed the legal
paperwork to create the Viet son
foundation and then began raising funds
through events such as a kickball
tournament a walkathon and a school
dress down day they also set up a
website that has attracted donations
from Florida to California so far the
Viet son foundation has awarded
elementary school scholarships to six
Vietnamese children and it's purchased a
year's worth of text books and school
supplies for four other young students
ladies and gentlemen for refusing to
accept the conditions he encountered in
Vietnam as inevitable for creating a
foundation that is given impoverished
Vietnamese children the chance to get an
education and for being an outstanding
role model for other young people we are
proud to name Jeremy Bowie a prudential
spirit of community national honoree
hi everyone oh wow this is truly amazing
everybody here it's been a great time in
DC and I like to thank my parents who
gave me the opportunity to have a great
life here in America they they came here
during the Vietnam War my mom came over
on a boat and my dad left and when the
Americans pulled out during the war so
I'm and they came here with literally
with nothing and built up their lives
through education and gave us my
brothers and I a great life here in
America and it's we came to Vietnam two
years ago and saw these children that
couldn't afford to go to school and had
no way of going to school because they
had to work long days for their parents
so we had to do something and and to get
them back in school where they should be
and it means a lot to meet all these
amazing people and having everybody in
our own community back in enfield
connecticut helping us and throughout
the whole country and i appreciate
meeting everybody here who's equally
amazing as i am and thanks for
everything everyone thank you
you